const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",i="insurance",a=200,t=120,o=[{id:68,question:"The buyer of insurance product is",option:{a:"Agent",b:"Broker",c:"Insured",d:"Insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:226,question:"Another name for utmost good faith",option:{a:"expirit - de - corps",b:"uberrimae fidei",c:"caveat emptor",d:"proximate cause"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:253,question:"Payment by the insurer to the insured out of sympathy is known as",option:{a:"utmost good faith",b:"proximate cause",c:"peril",d:"ex-gratia payment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:345,question:"Which  of  the  following  functions  is  related  to  life assurance contract? Benefits are",option:{a:"determined  on  the  happening  of  insured  event",b:"determined by the indemnity doctrine",c:"determined at the inception of the policy",d:"assessed by the extent of the loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:199,question:"The policy that provides protection for goods or cargoes and ships against the perils of the sea is",option:{a:"Fire",b:"Marine",c:"Aviation",d:"Credit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:201,question:"Insurance is defined as",option:{a:"risking of loss",b:"pooling of risk",c:"gathering of risk",d:"waiving of risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:205,question:"The coming together of minds of  the two parties to the insurance contract is called",option:{a:"surrender value",b:"acceptance",c:"consensus ad-idem",d:"adhesion"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:228,question:"Contribution will only arise when",option:{a:"two or more parties disagree",b:"two or more parties are promisor",c:"two or more policies of indemnity exist",d:"one policy of indemnity exist"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:111,question:"Which of the following is a temporary document given to the insured in an insurance contract?",option:{a:"Cover note",b:"Subrogation",c:"Policy document",d:"Reinsurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:24,question:"Ade insured his property for N= 350,000.00. The property is subject to average condition. He suffered a loss amounting to N= 30,000.00 with the value of the property at the time of loss to be N= 370,000.00. How much will the insurer pay?",option:{a:"N= 14,583.33",b:"N= 28,378.38",c:"N= 30,000.00",d:"N= 31,714.29"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:212,question:"An insurance contract which does not involve mutuality of agreement in which only one of the parties involved in the contract makes promises that are legally binding is called",option:{a:"double contract",b:"single contract",c:"multilateral contract",d:"unilateral contract"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:218,question:"Non- indemnity insurance means that the assured can",option:{a:"be restored back to his former position",b:"not be restored back to his former position",c:"be brought back to contract",d:"not be brought back to contract"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:263,question:"Replacement of damaged property by the insurance company is",option:{a:"arbitration",b:"negotiation",c:"Re-instatement",d:"rectification"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:149,question:"The wrongful act willfully committed by either the master or the prejudice of either the owner or crew to the chatterer of the ship is",option:{a:"Barratry",b:"Caveat emptor",c:"Bailee",d:"Jettison"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:266,question:"One of this is the evidence of insurance contract",option:{a:"schedule",b:"policy",c:"proposal form",d:"endorsement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:72,question:"The risks which affect the society and whose causes are beyond human control is",option:{a:"particular risk",b:"static",c:"fundamental",d:"speculative"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:36,question:"The professional service required for effective claims administration by insurers would be provided by",option:{a:"loss assessors",b:"risk managers",c:"loss adjusters",d:"claims consultants"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:162,question:"The essential value of valid contract that states that the parties to a contract must be in perfect agreement and have a common mind is",option:{a:"Consideration",b:"Perpetual existence",c:"Excess",d:"Consensus ad-idem"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:338,question:"The amount charged when a ship overstays at the port under a marine contract is",option:{a:"penalty",b:"fine",c:"overcharge",d:"demurrage"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:46,question:"The alternative to seeking for surrender value in a life assurance contract is",option:{a:"automatic non - forfeiture",b:"revival condition",c:"paid-up policy",d:"standing order"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:314,question:"In which of the following policies is <em>certificate of insurance</em>  used?",option:{a:"Burglary insurance",b:"Product liability insurance",c:"Employer’s liability insurance",d:"Money insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:50,question:"Which of the following is not a function of an insurance broker?",option:{a:"Assisting clients in paying premium",b:"Maintaining proper records of claims",c:"Assisting clients in connecting to insurers",d:"Assisting clients in effecting uninsured loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:90,question:"Any circumstance that promotes the probability of a loss is called",option:{a:"accident",b:"hazard",c:"loss",d:"risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:256,question:"Another name for the assured is",option:{a:"insurance company’s client",b:"insurance broker",c:"insurance company",d:"insurance agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:170,question:"The type of questionnaire drawn up by   insurers, requesting certain information to assess risk is --------- form",option:{a:"Acceptance",b:"Compensation",c:"Credit",d:"Proposal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:56,question:"A fundamental condition which must be filled  by the  insured for compensation is",option:{a:"warranty",b:"obligation",c:"interest",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:237,question:"A card used by motorist in the West African sub-region is called",option:{a:"insurance certificate",b:"insurance register",c:"insurance green card",d:"Ecowas brown card"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:175,question:"Spreading of risk to ensure that no insurer is liquidated by the occurrence of a large loss is the concept of",option:{a:"Insurance",b:"Re insurance",c:"Renewal",d:"Treaty"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:135,question:"The person who calculate the amount given to the insured if he does not want to continue with the contract of insurance is called",option:{a:"Actuary",b:"Insurance agent",c:"Insurance broker",d:"Assessor loss adjuster"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:336,question:"The meaning of with <em>profit policy</em>  in life assurance is that the sum assured is paid",option:{a:"without profit",b:"with profit",c:"with interest",d:"without interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:125,question:"A card used by motorist in the West African sub-region is called",option:{a:"Brown card",b:"Certificate",c:"Insurance card",d:"visa card"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:109,question:"In the utmost good faith principle, the value of the subject matter should",option:{a:"Be over stated",b:"Understated",c:"Not be stated",d:"Not be overstated nor understated"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:20,question:"A residential building built beside a petrol filling station is described as a",option:{a:"risk",b:"hazard",c:"peril",d:"liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:292,question:"Speailative risks are",option:{a:"insurable risk",b:"non insurable risk",c:"financial risk",d:"non financial risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:188,question:"Method of providing indemnity whereby subject matter is being restored to its former position is",option:{a:"Repairs",b:"Cash",c:"Reinstatement",d:"Replacement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:299,question:"The party who proposes to the insurance company to insure his properly is called",option:{a:"offeree",b:"offeror",c:"acceptance party",d:"offer client"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:241,question:"Policy condition which are automatically applicable and not stated in the contract of agreement is known as",option:{a:"agreed condition",b:"agreed negotiation",c:"implied condition",d:"expressed condition"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:58,question:"In insurance contract the insured is the",option:{a:"offeror",b:"offeree",c:"Actuary",d:"Ofree"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:295,question:"Business interruption insurance can also be called",option:{a:"consequential loss",b:"constructive loss",c:"partial  loss",d:"general loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:326,question:"What is the full meaning of “NCRIB” in the insurance industry?",option:{a:"National  Council of  Registered Insurance  Brokers",b:"Nigerian  Council of  Registered Insurance  Brokers",c:"Nigerian Corporation of Registered Insurance Brokers",d:"National Corporation of Registered Insurance Brokers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:152,question:"The uncertainty of an event occurring is known as",option:{a:"Hazard",b:"Risk",c:"Loss",d:"Accident"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:82,question:"The cause of a loss is known as",option:{a:"Risk",b:"Peril",c:"Hazard",d:"Moral"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:172,question:"A financial compensation sufficient to return the insured back to his original position after loss is known as",option:{a:"Deposit",b:"Loan",c:"Indemnity",d:"Overdraft"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:275,question:"A contract which has no legal effect is called",option:{a:"void policy",b:"voidable policy",c:"legal policy",d:"formal policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:293,question:"The form of risk that can easily be calculated and estimated is known as",option:{a:"non insurable risk",b:"non-financial risk",c:"speculative risk",d:"insurable risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:89,question:"Indemnity is provided through the following media except",option:{a:"cash",b:"commission",c:"reinstatement",d:"repair"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:16,question:"In the preparation of food for eat - in - customers, the cooks made a mistake in using excess quantity of an 	ingredient. A customer ate and  suffered  poisoning. 	Which policy of the operator would pick this liability?",option:{a:"Public liability",b:"Personal liability",c:"All risks insurance",d:"Loss of profit insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:274,question:"A reinsurance contract in which the reassured agrees to offer and the reinsurer agrees to accept all risks of certain size within a defined class is",option:{a:"underwriting",b:"treaty",c:"tort",d:"syndicate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:328,question:"The cover that is taken at the option of the motor vehicle owner is",option:{a:"a comprehensive cover",b:"an act only cover",c:"a third party only cover",d:"a special type cover"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:222,question:"A contract that is contrary to public policy is",option:{a:"valid contract",b:"legal contract",c:"illegal contract",d:"voidable contract"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:203,question:"The premium paid by the insured to the insurance company is",option:{a:"capital",b:"commission",c:"common fund",d:"consideration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:153,question:"The provider of protection to an insurance  company against the excess risk it has given insurance covers is called",option:{a:"Assurer",b:"Insuring",c:"Reinsurer",d:"Insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:69,question:"The seller of insurance product is",option:{a:"Insurer",b:"Insured",c:"Broker",d:"Agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:147,question:"An insurance cover for lawyers, accountants and brokers is",option:{a:"Employment",b:"Professional",c:"Public",d:"Product"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:156,question:"A temporary certificate to show that a cover is in existence is called",option:{a:"Policy",b:"Certificate",c:"Cover note",d:"Claim slip"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:117,question:"There must  be  a  close  connection  between  the loss actually suffered and the risk is relating to the principle  of",option:{a:"Abandonment",b:"Proximate cause",c:"Utmost good faith",d:"Adhesion"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:192,question:"The process of changing anything wrong with the policy to make it current is",option:{a:"Endorsement",b:"Specification",c:"Rectification",d:"Correction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:231,question:"The statement “ I to the best of my knowledge hereby confirm that the statements contained in this prosal form are true and correct” represents",option:{a:"confirmation",b:"declaration",c:"witnessing",d:"humility"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:276,question:"The contract aimed at providing specific payment at regular intervals for a fixed   period or for life is",option:{a:"accident",b:"annuity",c:"average",d:"term"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:232,question:"When the proposer fails to fill the proposal form truthfully, the contract will become",option:{a:"voidable",b:"illegal",c:"void",d:"enforceable"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:193,question:"A syndicate or an insurance company that transfer risk under re-insurance is",option:{a:"Cede",b:"Cession",c:"Commutation",d:"Cedant"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:129,question:"The  payment  made  by  underwriter  as  a  form  of  	kindness  without  admission  of  liability  so  as  to maintain goodwill is known as ------------",option:{a:"Kindness payment",b:"Ex-gratia payment",c:"Favour payment",d:"Claim"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:55,question:"A  statement  of  fact  that  the insured must have an interest in the object of the contract is called",option:{a:"warranty",b:"insurable interest",c:"subrogation",d:"object interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:88,question:"A miss statement of fact that is made by the insured or his broker to an underwriter during negotiation is called",option:{a:"annuity",b:"misrepresentation",c:"endorsement",d:"disclosure"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:191,question:"Cover note usually run for about",option:{a:"21 days",b:"one month",c:"12 months",d:"3 month"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:230,question:"one of these is a content of a proposal form",option:{a:"children of the proposer",b:"education of the proposer",c:"occupation of the proposer",d:"educational"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:45,question:"The consideration paid for insurance contract is",option:{a:"money",b:"commission",c:"premium",d:"fee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:43,question:"To which of the following parties does the principle of utmost good faith apply in a contract of insurance?",option:{a:"The proposer only",b:"The insurer only",c:"The insurer and proposer",d:"The third party and insured"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:139,question:"Consequential loss is also known as",option:{a:"Business interruption insurance",b:"Credit insurance",c:"Excess loss",d:"Property insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:119,question:"Which of the following is not a principle of insurance",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Insurable risk",c:"Subrogation",d:"Insurable interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:254,question:"If the insured does not want the contract to continue he receives",option:{a:"surrender value",b:"consideration",c:"premium",d:"commission"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:348,question:"The principle of maritime law which makes owners of a ship and cargo share in a loss incurred voluntarily is",option:{a:"special average",b:"general average",c:"specific average",d:"particular average"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:195,question:"Application by the insured to the insurer for the payment of money due under his contract of insurance is",option:{a:"Proof",b:"Evidence",c:"Claim",d:"Compensation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:78,question:"Factors which may influence the occurrence of a loss is",option:{a:"Risk",b:"Loss",c:"Peril",d:"Hazard"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:114,question:"One of the essential features of insurance contract is",option:{a:"Premium",b:"Subrogation",c:"Interest",d:"Disclosure"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:242,question:"A written amendment in addition or alterations to the information stated in the policy is called",option:{a:"endorsement",b:"specification",c:"construction",d:"attestation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:265,question:"Which of the following risks is covered by insurance policy?",option:{a:"an investment loss on the stock market",b:"dishonesty of an employee leading to fraud",c:"failure of a business venture",d:"rise and fall of prices of goods in the market"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:209,question:"In insurance, uncertainty of loss means",option:{a:"hazard",b:"risk",c:"accident",d:"earthquake"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:288,question:"Marine  losses are divided into",option:{a:"actual total and total loss",b:"total loss and partial loss",c:"partial loss and actual loss",d:"average loss and partial loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:103,question:"Below are insurable policies except",option:{a:"Earthquake",b:"Fire",c:"Life",d:"Marine"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:155,question:"------------ is the protection which the insured buys for his risk",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Compensation",c:"Cover",d:"Subrogation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:340,question:"The  difference  between  theft  and burglary insurance lies in evidence of",option:{a:"pilfering  of insured items",b:"removal of insured items by tricks",c:"forceful violent entry or exit affecting insured items",d:"threat leading to loss of insured items"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:54,question:"The facts which might influence any party’s willingness to enter the contract or reject it is called",option:{a:"insurable fact",b:"insurance fact",c:"insured fact",d:"material fact"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:40,question:"The owner of a life assurance policy who enters into an agreement to sell the ownership of the policy and beneficiary rights upon the death of the insured is called",option:{a:"an underwriter",b:"a aviator",c:"a factor",d:"an assessor"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:140,question:"Subrogation principle can be applied in the following insurance policies except in",option:{a:"motor",b:"Life",c:"Marine",d:"Aviation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:142,question:"Amount paid to the beneficiary upon the death of the insured is",option:{a:"Premium",b:"Compensation",c:"Declaration",d:"Death benefit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:207,question:"The legal right that a person must have to enable him or her to insure his or her property is known as",option:{a:"freedom",b:"franchise",c:"insurable interest",d:"Access right"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:138,question:"The duty of the loss adjuster in insurance claims is to",option:{a:"Make loss",b:"Prevent loss",c:"Safeguard loss",d:"Recommend appropriate payment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:202,question:"In a contract of insurance, a firm statement is usually made by a person known as the",option:{a:"offeror",b:"offeree",c:"insur",d:"client"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:136,question:"The amount given to the insured if he does not want the contract to continue is called",option:{a:"Insurance broker",b:"Premium",c:"Surrender value",d:"Assessor loss adjuster"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:174,question:"A marine policy that provider cover for the construction of sea vessels is called --------- policy",option:{a:"Building",b:"Mixed",c:"Port",d:"Valued"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:13,question:"The class of non-life insurance policy where cover note is issued is",option:{a:"fire insurance",b:"burglary insurance",c:"motor insurance",d:"fidelity guarantee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:334,question:"The process of  assessing  risks  in  insurance  and classifying them according to their degree of insurability so  that  the  appropriate  rate  may  be  assigned  is",option:{a:"inspecting",b:"underwriting",c:"surveying",d:"evaluating"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:133,question:"When an insured person admits that he has indemnified, he means that",option:{a:"The damage proper by has been recovered",b:"He was paid premium fully",c:"The insurance company has restored him to his former position",d:"He was paid his premium fully"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:229,question:"One of the following is a condition for contribution",option:{a:"bilateral interest",b:"multilatual interest",c:"two subject matter",d:"common subject matter"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:221,question:"A contract which has no legal effect is called",option:{a:"voidable contract",b:"legal contract",c:"void contract",d:"valid contract"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:244,question:"The process of transferring risk from one insurer to another is called",option:{a:"contribution",b:"re-insurance",c:"re-processing",d:"re-activating"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:337,question:"The  document issued by  the  insurer when there is a change in the particulars of a risk insured is",option:{a:"endorsement",b:"certificate",c:"voucher",d:"policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:145,question:"Factor that causes an exposure to injury, loss or damage is",option:{a:"Risk",b:"Hazard",c:"Peril",d:"Accident"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:171,question:"The shifting of responsibility of one’s own losses to another is known as ---------- transfer",option:{a:"Fund",b:"Risk",c:"Business",d:"Policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:102,question:"Insurable interest means",option:{a:"Interest gained on money in a bank",b:"Interest payable on a loan",c:"Financial interest a person has in something he expects to inherit",d:"The financial interest a person has in something of value"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:279,question:"A policy that covers the peril of the sea is",option:{a:"aviation",b:"marine",c:"life",d:"fire"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:160,question:"The monetary consideration paid by the insured to the insurers for the insurance granted by the policy is called",option:{a:"Premium",b:"Money",c:"Price",d:"Benefit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:178,question:"Indemnity is provided through the following media except",option:{a:"Cash",b:"Commission",c:"Reinstatement",d:"Repair"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:233,question:"Proposal form is used in the following classes of insurance except",option:{a:"Accident",b:"theft",c:"life",d:"large risk of fire"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:312,question:"In a life assurance contract, when does  the  principle of insurable interest arise?",option:{a:"At the beginning of the contract",b:"At the time of claim",c:"At the middle of the contract",d:"At the time of payment of premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:284,question:"Return premium is the same thing as",option:{a:"premium payment",b:"premium refund",c:"premium tax",d:"premium bonus"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:258,question:"One of the following is necessary to meet uncertainties in future",option:{a:"profit",b:"capital",c:"borrowing",d:"insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:282,question:"The periodic payment made by the insured to the insurer as financial cost of obtaining insurance",option:{a:"annuity",b:"premium",c:"claim",d:"dividend"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:214,question:"Assurance is a contract that is based on",option:{a:"negativity",b:"possibility",c:"positivity",d:"probability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:327,question:"Which of the following is not a function of an insurance underwriter?",option:{a:"Determining rates and coverage for the risk",b:"Deciding whether to take the risk",c:"Looking for an insurer to take the risk",d:"Deciding whether to reject the risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:294,question:"A risk that has its origin in the activities of an individual and the effects borne by this individual is called",option:{a:"pure risk",b:"particular risk",c:"speculative risk",d:"fundamental risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:104,question:"The term pooling of risks in insurance means that",option:{a:"Many who face risks pay premium so that those who suffer loss may be reimbursed",b:"Insurance companies share heavy losses",c:"Insurance company re-assures with another",d:"Insurance companies operates pool betting business"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:144,question:"The date on which an insurance or reinsurance contract comes into force is known as",option:{a:"Starting point date",b:"Inception date",c:"Beginning date",d:"Commencement date"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:32,question:"A contract sold  by  insurance companies that  pay  a monthly or  quarterly income  benefit for the  life  of a person is",option:{a:"endowment",b:"annuity",c:"income",d:"freight"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:319,question:"What is  the  maximum  liability which the insurer can pay on a particular loss?",option:{a:"Average",b:"Sum insured",c:"Franchise",d:"Excess"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:239,question:"The part of a policy form that shows the name and address of the company is known as",option:{a:"heading",b:"conclusion",c:"condition",d:"preamble"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:67,question:"Insurance contract is between",option:{a:"Broker and Agent",b:"Insured and Insurer",c:"Insurer  and Agent",d:"Insured and Agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:163,question:"A  Statement signed by the insured, certifying the Statement",option:{a:"Certificate",b:"Declaration",c:"Confirmation slip",d:"Accuracy statement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:128,question:"The continuation of insurance contract after expiration is",option:{a:"Renewal",b:"Revival",c:"Resuscitation",d:"Rejuvenation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"}],n={message:e,subject:i,status:200,total:120,data:o};export{o as data,n as default,e as message,a as status,i as subject,t as total};
